在我们开始之前，我想对如何
before we get going I want to do a
little bit of philosophizing about how
我们开始的一周开始就是在物理学中学习东西
it is we learn things in in physics at
the beginning of the week we started
用固体振动的玻尔兹曼模型，然后我们决定
with the Boltzmann model of vibrations
in solids and then we decided that
不太正确，因此我们必须使用固体的爱因斯坦模型对其进行改进
wasn't quite right so we had to improve
it with the Einstein model of the solid
那是相当不错的，但是没有正确的低温行为
and that was pretty good but it didn't
get the low-temperature behavior right
所以我们不得不用德拜固体理论对其进行改进，甚至
so we had to improve it with the Debye
theory of solids and that was even
更好，但今年晚些时候我们也将不得不对其进行改进
better but we're going to have to
improve it later on in the year as well
一个完全正确的问题是我们为什么不从中学到正确的东西
and a perfectly valid question is why
didn't we learn the right thing at the
开始，而不必经历所有这些错误的模型，并且
beginning and not have to go through all
of these models which are all wrong and
这不仅仅是因为我喜欢告诉您了解有关所有
it's not just because I like telling you
know history stories about how all of
这是开发出来的，但我们这样做的原因是因为这始终是我们的方式
this was developed but the reason we do
this is because this is always how we
在物理学中学习事物，即使它是
learn things in physics you always learn
the simple model even though it's
首先是错误的，因为这样容易思考，例如
incorrect first because it's a lot
easier to think about so for example you
首先要学习古典力学，这是不对的，因为你知道
learn in classical mechanics first and
it's not really right because you know
有相对论和量子力学，然后将它们叠加
there's special relativity and there's
quantum mechanics and you layer those on
回到顶部，但是您的直觉总是回到简单的模型上
top later but your intuition always
falls back to the simple model it's a
更容易思考，这就是我们这样做的原因，而这正是
lot easier to think about and that's why
we do this and this is exactly what
今天我们要谈论上次开始的金属时要做的
we're going to be doing today when we
talk about metals we started last time
金属和我们用于许多事物的简单原油模型是德鲁伊
metals and the simple crude model we use
for many many things is the druid
电子和金属的图片
apicture
of electrons and metals which is
基本上只是动力学理论。
basically just kinetic theory kinetic
theory for electrons for electrons and
在最后一次结束时，我们导出了dru来传递方程D动量DT
at the end of last time we derived the
dru to transport equation D momentum DT
等于在某些现象学散射上电子减去P上的力
equals the force on the electron minus P
over some phenomenological scattering
时间力是洛伦兹力的时间tau
time tau where the force is Lorentz
force the general force that the
电子的感觉，所以基本上只是牛顿方程，增加了阻力
electron feels so it's basically just
Newton's equation with an added drag
P超过tau的力P代表散射
force P over tau which sort of
represents scattering sort of slows the
现在，对于许多实验，电子都会以某种方式下降，我们将对此感兴趣
electron down in some way now for many
experiments we're going to be interested
在我们实际上正在进行某种稳态实验，您可能会应用
in we are actually doing some sort of
steady state experiment you might apply
稳定的电场，您可能会施加稳定的电流，并且您对此感兴趣
a steady electric field you might apply
a steady current and you're interested
处于稳定状态的结果，因此大大简化了寻找工作
in a steady state result so it's
simplifies things a lot to look for
稳态，所以DP DT等于零，所以我们尝试解决，使GP DT等于
steady states so DP DT equals zero so
let's try to solve that so GP DT equals
零，我们将在右侧施加力，因此我要使用的力
zero we'll put in the force on the right
hand side here so the force I'm going to
用洛伦兹力加V叉B代替，然后我们需要P超过tau
replace that by the Lorentz force plus V
cross B and then we need P over tau over
在这里，但是我要用tau的MV代替P，因为我们有一个速度
here but I'm going to replace P by M V
over tau just because we have a velocity
哦，这里有相同的速度，我们现在要在其中放置另一个速度
here oh there's the same velocity here
we'll put another velocity there now
速度是一个非常好的数量，但实际上不是你所需要的
velocity is a perfectly good quantity
but it's not actually what you are
有可能在实验中进行测量，而您更有可能进行测量
likely to measure in the experiment
which you're much more likely to measure
实验是电流密度电流密度与
an experiment is the current density
current density very closely related to
速度J是电子数或电子密度
velocity J is the number of electron or
the density of electrons density of
电子乘以电子上的电荷至负e乘以电子
electrons times the charge on the
electron goes to minus e times his
速度好，所以电流密度就是你拥有多少电子，但是
velocity okay so the current density is
just how many electrons you have but the
给他们充电，移动速度有多快，所以每次我有速度时
charge they have and how fast they're
moving so every time I have velocity in
该方程式我将插入J并除以N和负E
that equation I'm going to plug in J
instead and divide by an N and a minus E
第一步，我还要将e移到另一边
and one step I'm also going to move e
over to the other side and get this
方程e在整个J交叉B上等于1，然后在N平方的tau时间上等于M
equation e equals one over n e J cross B
and then plus M over N squared tau times
J对一次太多的步骤感到非常高兴，是的，所以我只是我
J is that good happy with that too many
steps at once yeah so I just I just
插入j4v，然后将D移动到另一侧
plugged in j4v
and then move D to the other side and
通过任何驱动器将其划分为我的密钥，好吧，所以这有两个术语
divide it through by any drive to my key
okay good so there's two terms in this
等式，我们称它们为两个不同的东西
equation and we'll call them two
different things
让我们将此称为e并行，我们将其称为e暂停
let's call this e parallel and we'll
call this e halt
我用这个画一个图，所以我们有一块金属
let me draw a diagram with this so we
have is we have a block of metal like
这将使电流像这样的电流流过金属
this we're going to run a current
through the metal like this current
像我们可能会施加磁场
density in content C out like that we
might apply a magnetic field
也许像这样的B垂直于金属，然后我们将有一个平行
maybe perpendicular to the metal like
this B and then we will have a parallel
在这个方向上的电场在那个方向上然后是霍尔垂直
in this direction electric field in that
direction and then a Hall perpendicular
电流和垂直于磁场以及一个大厅，它是
to the current and perpendicular to the
magnetic field as well a hall and it's
之所以称为霍尔电场是因为它是由埃德温·霍尔（Edwin Hall）发现的，
called the hall electric field because
it was discovered by Edwin Hall who is
正是在1879年进行了这类实验，他发现当他
doing exactly these kind of experiments
in 1879 and he discovered that when he
在磁场中使电流流过金属，最终导致
ran a current through a metal in a
magnetic field he ended up with an
垂直于它们两个的电场，您之前可能已经遇到过
electric field perpendicular both of
them you may have run into this before
这是洛伦兹力量的一个非常明显的结果，发生的是你在
it's a pretty clear result of the
Lorentz force what's happening is you're
使电子穿过材料，并且它们试图弯曲，因为
running electrons through the material
and they're trying to curve because of
磁场并建立一个电场，每个人都满意
the magnetic field and that builds up an
electric field good everyone happy with
差不多，所以让我们尝试了解一下这个方程
that more or less okay so let's try to
you know think about this equation a
让我们更简单地考虑一个磁场为零的简单情况
little more closely let's take a simple
case case one magnetic field equals zero
所以在那种情况下，我们只有电场让我绕过另一个
so in that case we just have electric
field let me turn it around the other
将J移到他们旁边的方式
way
move the J to their side so J the
然后，电流在m倍于电场的平方n上被平方
current is then n e squared Tao over m
times the electric field this quantity
这是电导率Sigma电导率这是电导率，因为
here is a conductivity Sigma
conductivity it's a conductivity because
它把电场与电流联系起来
it relates the electric field to the
current now the expression for the
我们在m上推导出e平方的Tao的电导率是Deuter
conductivity that we derived an e
squared Tao over m is the Deuter
电导率是我们将在Drude理论中计算出的电导率
conductivity is the conductivity we
would calculate in the Drude theory we
只是计算了一下，我们对什么是什么应该有一个很容易的直觉
just calculated it and we should have
pretty easy intuition for what's what's
继续讲，电导率具有最高密度的因素，因为
going on here the conductivity has a
factor of density up top because the
电子越多，电流就越多
more electrons you have the more current
you're going to get and the more
您将要获得的电导率是tau的系数
conductivity you're going to get it has
a factor of tau up top
因为越长的道越大道意味着更长的散射时间和更长的时间
because longer Tao bigger Tao means
longer scattering time and the longer
散布时间或更少的事情变得更好
scattering time you have or the less
things you have to run into the better
现在你的电导率会变成事实，我正在楼下，看起来有点
your conductivity is going to be now the
fact I'm mass downstairs looks a little
稍微复杂一点，但实际上如果质量等于F等于MA
bit more complicated but actually it
just comes from F equals MA if your mass
对于固定力来说很小，您的加速度必须更大，所以您
is small for a fixed force your
acceleration has to be larger so you
施加一定的固定力，如果电子质量较小，则电子运动得更快
apply out some fixed force the electrons
move faster if their mass were smaller
这就是为什么现在我们可能要问楼下传出大量东西的原因，或者保罗提请德
that's why the mass comes out downstairs
now we might ask or Paul drew de might
问这是一个好答案吗？
ask is this a good answer is this a bad
answer
现在我们实际上不知道，因为它是一个未知数
and right now we actually don't know
because how is some unknown number it's
他不知道如何计算的一些现象，我们只能把
some phenomena he doesn't know how to
calculate it we can just we have to put
从现象学上讲，所以实际上它几乎适合任何东西
it in phenomenologically so really it
would fit pretty much anything at this
点，所以你可能会想到它，你知道排序
point
so you might think of it you know sort
这反过来说明电导率的测量实际上是
of turn this on its head that
measurement of conductivity is actually
参数tau的度量正常，这通常是如何查看的
a measurement of the parameter tau okay
and that's frequently how it's viewed
好吧，让我们做一些稍微复杂一些的事
all right let's do a little something a
little bit more complicated case to case
B等于零的两个，我们可能会以多种方式思考
two which is B not equal to zero and
there are various ways we might think
关于B不等于零的一种可能
about B not equal to zero one
possibility of doing this experiment is
我们可能想像一下，假设我们知道，所以将其称为假设我们知道一对
we might imagine suppose we know so it's
called its to a suppose we know a couple
假设我们知道电子的密度，当然我们知道
things suppose we know the density of
our electrons of course we know the
电子上的电荷假设我们知道电流并且我们测量我们测量一个
charge on the electron suppose we know
the current and we measure we measure a
然后根据犹大理论停下来，我们知道然后我们得到一个磁场B
halt then according to Judah Theory we
then know then we get a magnetic field B
实际上，这是一种非常常用的测量磁场的方法
and in fact this is a very frequently
used method for measuring magnetic
在现场它被称为霍尔传感器，并且您知道它仍然经常在
fields it's known as a hall sensor and
you know it's still used frequently in
现在，让我们稍微详细一点
通常在这里，如果您在磁场中有电流，您将会得到一些东西
here generally if you have a current in
a magnetic field you will get something
的形式，我们定义此数量rhv cross j注意转订单
of the form we define this quantity
rhv cross j notice that turn the order
J和B在那边的-在这里这只是常用的定义
of J and B over there - over here this
is just a definition of a commonly used
称为霍尔系数的数量
quantity known as the Hall coefficient
所以嗯，你知道你是否知道J是什么，B就是II
so um you know if you know what J is you
know what B is measure II get the Hall
例如，系数如此正确，因此吸引了犹大理论比较
coefficient for example so right so in
drew the theory Judah Theory comparing
这个方程式，所以这是犹大理论中的B霍尔对不起G霍尔
to that equation so this is B Hall sorry
G Hall in Judah Theory comparing to that
那里的等式，霍尔系数RH在密度乘以1时得到-e减去
equation over there the hall coefficient
RH is 1 over density times - e the minus
信号来自这样一个事实，即我将这两个顺序颠倒了
sign comes from the fact that I flipped
the order of these two compared to over
那里的霍尔电场
there
so the Hall electric field that you
将测量与霍尔系数成正比，如果你是
would measure would be proportional to
the Hall coefficient here and if you're
试图建立一个霍尔传感器以找到准确的测量方法
trying to build a hall sensor in order
to find accurate ways of measuring
使用电子设备或使用电压测量结果产生的磁场
magnetic fields using electronics or
using voltage measurements you really
希望霍尔电压尽可能大，以便
want the hall voltage to be large as
large as possible so that you have a
要测量大电场，以便这样做，您通常会选择一个
large electric field to measure so to do
that what you do is you usually choose a
密度较小的材料，所以使用时要用较小的密度来变大
material with a small density so use use
use small density to get big to get big
大e和典型的霍尔传感器由半导体和其他材料制成
big e and typical Hall sensors are built
with semiconductors and other materials
电子密度很小，我们稍后将介绍半导体
that have a small electron density and
we'll come to semiconductors later on in
这个词现在让我们开始实验吧，大概是
the term now let's turn this experiment
now on its head probably the way that
保罗·德鲁（Paul Drude）对他的案子有一个想法，他可能不知道有什么问题，
Paul Drude a thought about it in his
case he probably knew no the dent up and
因此，在他的情况下，他可能知道磁场，电子电荷和
so in his case he probably knew the
magnetic field the electron charge and
当前测得的霍尔数和得到的结果
the current measured measure Hall and
what you get
你得到的是样品中电子的密度，因为他当然
what you get is the density of electrons
in your sample because of course he
不太了解他材料中的电子密度，所以让我们尝试一下
didn't know the density of electrons in
his materials well so let's try this
假设我们针对多种不同的材料执行此操作，因此我们将采用
suppose we do this for a bunch of
different materials so we'll take a
一堆金属，例如锂钠，钾，铜，铜
bunch of metals like lithium sodium
potassium copper are sort of typical
好的金属，保罗·犹大会注意到的第一件事是
good metals and the first thing that
Paul Judah would have noticed is that
对于所有这些金属，相对湿度均小于零，这是他所预测的
for all of these metals RH is less than
zero which is what he predicted by his
公式在这里，所以很多东西都很好，然后他可以实际输入
formula over here so that much is good
and then he can actually put in you know
测量e霍尔的幅度并尝试提取电子的密度。
measure the magnitude of e Hall and try
to extract the density of electrons and
他得到的是每个原子约0.8个电子，这里约1.2
what he would have gotten was about 0.8
electrons per atom here about 1.2
每个原子电子约1.1个电子/原子1.5个电子/个
electrons per atom here about 1.1
electrons per atom 1.5 electrons per
原子似乎是个合理的数字，您知道想知道几个电子
atom seems like reasonable numbers a
couple of electrons you know wondering
每个原子或多或少有一个电子，这是一个好答案吗？
one electron per atom more or less is
this a good answer is this a bad answer
好吧，如果你考虑一秒钟，你会记得你的周期表
well if you think about it for a second
you'll remember your periodic table
铜是元素周期表中的第29个元素，因此它具有29个质子
copper is the twenty-ninth element on
the periodic table so it has 29 protons
和29个电子，我们测得每个原子1.5个电子
and 29 electrons and we measured 1.5
electrons per atom
其他27.5到哪里去了，所以这可能有点令人费解
where'd the other 27.5 go so this might
have been a little bit puzzling to to
犹大，但实际上我们现在对原子结构有所了解
Judah but actually now that we know a
little bit about the atomic structure we
了解原子的壳结构，我们对化学有一点了解
know about the shell structure of atoms
we know a little bit about chemical
键合，我们甚至会在稍后的内容中谈论化学键合
bonding we'll even talk a little bit
about chemical bonding later on in the
一年，我们知道实际上一个原子中的许多电子实际上在
year and we know that in fact many of
the electrons in an atom are actually in
这些核心轨道电子非常靠近原子核的轨道
orbitals very close to the to the
nucleus these core orbital electrons are
基本上卡住了，所以核心轨道上的littlez电子或明显的电子
basically stuck so core orbitals
littlez electrons or overt electrons
不要移动唯一能移动外壳电子的电子，也就是
don't move the only ones that do move
outer shell electrons also known as
价电子
valence electrons
移动，因此在固体中运行的电子是
move so the electrons that are running
around in the in the solid are the
所谓的价电子，您知道化学作用，实际上我们知道
so-called valence electrons and you know
do from chemistry we actually know how
这些材料具有许多价电子，实际上所有这四个
many valence electrons these materials
have and in fact all these four
材料的化合价为1，意味着在最外层壳中只有一个电子
materials have valence one meaning only
one electron in the outermost shell so
如果我们假设只有最外面的电子移动最外面的电子
if we assume only the outermost
electrons move the ones in the outermost
壳，我们应该预测每个原子一个电子
shell
we should predict one electron per atom
实际上，您知道与测得的结果相当一致
and that's actually you know in fairly
good agreement with what is measured
从实验上来说，这对于juda理论非常有用
experimentally so that's pretty good for
for juda theory we get roughly one
每个原子移动的电子，所以我们可能会为成功感到鼓舞
electron per atom moving around so we
might you know emboldened by our success
我们可能会尝试其他一些材料，所以让我们尝试一些价
we might try some other materials so
let's try some with valence to valence
等于2我们有像铍这样的材料我们有镁
equals two we have materials like
beryllium we have magnesium
他们两个都有价，突然之间我们遇到了一个大问题
both of them have valence two and all of
a sudden we have a big problem the big
问题是它的相对湿度霍尔系数现在大于零，这是
problem is it RH the Hall coefficient is
now greater than zero and this is
从这张犹大计算机的图片中完全令人困惑的是，应该
completely puzzling from this picture of
Judah computer says that it should be
只是密度乘以负电荷的电子电荷，所以
just the density times the charge of the
electron which is negative and so
在犹大理论中，我们不可能得到霍尔系数
there's no way in Judah Theory we're
going to get a Hall coefficient which is
积极，这一定使保罗·德鲁德（Paul Drude）非常困惑，并在当年晚些时候
positive and this must have puzzled Paul
Drude a terribly and later on the year
当我们研究材料的能带结构时会明白为什么
when we study band structure of
materials will understand why this is
但看起来好像发生了两件事之一，可能是
but it kind of looks like one of two
things is going on possibility one is
电子密度由于某种原因变为负数
that the density of electrons has gone
negative for some reason if that makes
任何有意义的可能性二是充电
any sense
possibility two is that the charge
携带电荷的东西不是电子
carrier the thing that's moving around
carrying the charge is not the electron
但是其他带有正电荷的东西似乎都没有
but something else with a positive
charge neither of those seem to make
现在很有道理，但希望以后会更有意义
much sense right now but they'll make a
little bit more sense later on hopefully
但是你知道犹大是一个非常勇敢的人，他决定我们要去
but you know Judah was a very brave
person and he decided that we're going
忽略这两种材料，这些材料似乎不适合它们的价
to ignore these two materials that don't
seem to fit the materials with valence
两个霍尔系数为正，我们将继续尝试
two that have Hall coefficient positive
and we're going to go ahead and try to
计算动力学理论或犹大理论的其他数量
calculate some other quantity
that kinetic theory or Judah theory
应该可以预测，您去年和一年以前学习了动力学理论
should be able to predict now you
studied kinetic theory last year and one
您能在动力学理论中计算的事物是热的
of the things that you were able to
calculate in kinetic theory was thermal
电导率我不会进行整个计算，因为它是
conductivity I'm not going to go through
the whole calculation because it's
您去年可能学得很好的东西可能不值得
something that you probably learned very
well last year it's probably not worth
再次经历，但我会写下答案，你可能应该
going through again but I'll write down
the answer that you probably well should
可能看起来很熟悉单原子气体的导热系数
probably look familiar the thermal
conductivity for a monatomic gas is
颗粒密度每颗粒热容量的三分之一，这是N之上的CV
one-third the density of particles heat
capacity per particle this is CV over N
然后有一个速度和一个散射长度，即速度
and then there's a velocity and a
scattering length which is velocity
乘以散射时间，在动力学理论中，我们可以将速度设为
times the scattering time and in kinetic
theory we can take the velocity to be
pi乘以pi的倍数为8 KBT的平方根
square root of eight KBT over pi times
the mass does this all look familiar is
去年大概有点熟悉，希望还可以，所以我们要做的是
vaguely familiar from last year
hopefully okay so what we do is we
实际上只是将其插入V平方，因为它发生了
actually just plug this in it's going to
be V squared because because it occurs
在两个地方将插入动力学理论CD在N上的表达式
in two places will plug in the
expression from kinetic theory CD over N
是经典气体物理学的三分之二kb，而我们得到的是热
is three-halves kb from classical gas
physics and what we get is the thermal
电导率在pi上是4，所以让我们看一下PI就是从这里下来的
conductivity is 4 over pi so the let's
see so the PI comes from down here
平方之后，我猜我们那里有一个2，它取消了8以使
having gotten squared I guess we got a 2
over there which cancel the 8 to make a
4那么我们在n上有n tau KB平方T，所以这是对
4 then we have n tau K B squared T over
m so that's the prediction for the
在犹大理论中的热导率现在我们再次有这个问题是
thermal conductivity in in judah theory
now again we have this question is this
一个好答案还是一个不好的答案，我们真的不知道，因为我们有
a good answer or is this a bad answer
and we don't really know because we have
这个tau这个等式中的未知数量tau但是还不错
this tau this unknown quantity tau in
this equation but it's not so bad
因为我们也有Sigma是t大于m的平方的平方，我们可以看一下比率
这两个数量中的1个，然后去掉tau，所以我们做的就是
of these two quantities and get rid of
tau so let's do that we'll take what is
称为L洛伦兹burr洛伦兹编号这不是
known as L the Lorentz
burr lorentz number number this is not
实际上是洛伦兹转型和洛伦兹力量的同一个人
actually the same guy who is Lorentz
transformations and Lorentz force
这是洛伦兹（Lorenz），他名字中没有T，每个人似乎都有洛伦兹（Lorentz）号
this is Lorenz without the T in his name
Lorentz number everyone seems to have
1800年代在德国同名啊
the same name in Germany in the 1800s ah
我们可以将导热率与T乘以Sigma的比率
we so we can take the ratio of the
thermal conductivity to T times Sigma
在这里，Taos取消了，我们只剩下四个PI和KB / e平方
here the Taos cancel and we're left with
just four over PI and KB / e squared
就是这样，当您输入数字时，此结果是10的1倍
that's it and this result while you put
in numbers you discover it's 1 times 10
到每开尔文平方减去-8瓦欧姆，这个结果有点
to the minus 8 watt ohms per Kelvin
squared and this result is kind of
有趣，因为这就是我们所说的通用性，它并不依赖于
interesting because it's it's what we
call universal it doesn't depend on
温度与电子的质量无关
temperature it doesn't depend on the
mass of the electron it doesn't depend
电子的散射时间与电子的密度无关
on the scattering time of the electrons
doesn't pend on the density of electrons
除了这些基本数量之外，它不依赖任何其他因素
it doesn't depend on anything except
these fundamental quantities Boltzmann's
常数和电子的电荷，这是一个有趣的预测
constant and the charge of the electron
it's kind of an interesting prediction
实际上，洛伦兹数固定为L的事实对于
and in fact the fact that the Lorentz
number is fixed L the same the same for
所有材料的所有材料在所有场合都是已知的
all materials for all materials was
known in all t t um this is known as the
维生素Franz法维生素Franz，自1800年代中期以来就广为人知，
vitamin Franz law vitamin Franz and it
was known since the mid 1800s and no one
有一个最雾的想法，为什么它是真的，他们只是测量了维生素和弗朗兹
had the foggiest idea why it was true
they just measured it vitamin and Franz
是德国人，他们喜欢测量热导率电
were Germans who liked to measure things
like thermal conductivity electrical
电导率在1800年代中期，他们注意到，如果采用该比率
conductivity in the mid-1800s and they
noticed that if you take this ratio it
我猜如果我们想成为所有材料的结果几乎相同
comes out pretty much the same for all
materials I guess if we want to be
实际上，对于锂来说，它的精确度是2.2瓦乘以10
precise about it in fact for lithium it
comes out about 2.2 watt times 10 to the
铜的每开尔文平方减去8瓦欧姆，铁约为2.0
minus 8 watt ohms per Kelvin squared for
copper it's about 2.0 for iron
大约是2.6，所以非常接近犹大的
it's about 2.6 so it's pretty close to
judah's
预测好吧，它偏离了两倍，但至少它是正确的
prediction okay it's off by a factor of
two but at least it's in the right
球场这是一个非常粗糙的理论，在犹大之前没有人有任何想法
ballpark it's a very crude theory and
before Judah no one had the had any idea
为什么要为所有材料完全固定这个比例，所以这是
why this ratio should be fixed for all
materials all and at all so this was
确实向前迈出了一大步，我们应该拥有直觉
really a great step forward and the
intuition that we should have in our
头实际上不是那么复杂的直觉应该是
heads is actually not that complicated
the intuition should be that whether
我们正在考虑传热或他们在考虑什么
we're thinking about heat transport or
whatever they're thinking about
电传输我们实际上只是在考虑电子在运动
electrical transport we're really just
thinking about electrons moving if we're
考虑到常规电导率，我们有点在数
thinking about regular conductivity
we're sort of counting how many
电子移动，每个电子上都有一定量的电荷，而
electrons move and each electron has a
certain amount of charge on it whereas
如果我们在考虑导热系数，我们仍在计算
if we're thinking about thermal
conductivity we're still counting how
许多电子在运动，但是每个电子在运动一定量的
many electrons are moving but each
electron is moving a certain amount of
热量与温度成正比，因此热量比
heat which is proportional to
temperature so that ratio of thermal
电导率除以温度，然后除以常规电导率
conductivity divided by temperature then
divided by regular conductivity should
大致恒定，因为在所有情况下，您都只是在数
come out roughly constant because in
both in all cases you're just counting
可以移动的电子数，所以这是一个非常好的结果
the number of electrons that move okay
so this was a really good result from
来自犹大的会议，解释了维南法和弗朗茨法，但其中有一个
meeting from from Judah explaining the
vinum and Franz law but there's a really
大难题，而难题在于，我们过去使用了相当容易的陈述
big puzzle and the puzzle is that we
used we used rather glibly the statement
N上的CV为三分之二kb，对于
the CV over N is three-halves kb which
is a perfectly good result for a
单原子气体，但对于金属中的电子而言并非如此
monatomic gas but it's just not true for
electrons in the metal not true for
金属中的电子为什么不能很好地测量，我们发现它不是
electrons in metal why not
well we measured it and we saw it's not
真实记住金属中的热容量是立方T，我们
true remember in metals the heat
capacity is alpha T cubed and we
将此alpha识别为振动或Debye Theory加gamma
identified this alpha as being
vibrations or Debye Theory plus gamma
乘以T，实际上，如果您将此伽马乘以T，对于金属来说是特殊的，所以这是
times T and in fact if you this gamma
times T is special for metals so this is
电子在金属中以及任何周围流动的热容量
the heat capacity of the electrons
running around in the metal and for any
合理的温度伽玛乘以T远小于三分之二Kb
reasonable temperature gamma times T is
much much less than three halves Kb as
只要T不是巨大的，就意味着您知道的巨大
long as T is not ginormous
enormous that means huge like you know
只要T不为10,000开尔文10,000开尔文伽马T远小于
10,000 Kelvin as long as T is not 10,000
Kelvin gamma T is much less than
即使我们使用三分之二的Kb
three-halves Kb
so somehow or other even though we use
这东西显然是不正确的，我们用电子给了热量
this thing that was clearly incorrect we
use we gave the electrons the heat
每个容量可减少三分之二KB，而实际上如果测量热量
capacity of three-halves KB each whereas
in fact if you measure the heat capacity
金属的热容量不只是唯一的热容量
of the metal that heat capacity is just
not there the only heat capacity the
电子具有的这个伽马乘以T远小于
electrons have is this gamma times T
which is much much less than
三分之二Kb，那么我们如何正确地处理这件事呢
three-halves Kb so how did we get this
right what what what's going on here
好了，这里的问题这里的问题实际上变得更加明显
well the problem here the problem here
actually becomes much much more obvious
如果我们看其他数量，我们来看看热电特性
if we look at some other quantities
let's look at thermoelectric properties
热电性能电性能是一种
thermo electric properties electric
properties properties this is a kind of
我们要看的实验这里是一块金属，我们要运行电流
experiment we want to look at here's a
block of metal we want to run a current
所以这是电流源，我们将电流流过金属
so here's a current source we run the
current through the metal so the current
通过这种方式将电子拖过金属，然后因为电流是
drags electrons through the metal this
way and then because the current is
穿过金属，这意味着电子正在穿过金属
moving through the metal it means the
electrons are moving through the metal
因此热量就是我让电子以这种方式移动
and therefore heat is I just have the
electrons moving this way a current
向相反的方向移动，但是电子以这种方式移动，因此
moves in the opposite direction but the
electron is moving this way so then the
加热时，热电流被拖向同一方向，因为每个电子
heat the heat current gets dragged in
the same direction because each electron
用它拖动一定量的热量，所以可以定义J q JQ现在
is dragging a certain amount of heat
with it so one can define J q JQ is now
热流密度热流密度J q等于某个系数
the heat current density heat current
density J q is equal to some coefficient
pi乘以常规电流密度J和pi称为珀耳帖
pi times the regular current density J
and pi is known as the Peltier
珀尔帖系数，这称为
coefficient Peltier coefficient and this
is known as a Peltier effect after
先生。佩莱捷（Pelletier）在1834年发现了这种效应，
mr. Pelletier who discovered this effect
in 1834 another one of these people from
不管怎样，无论如何，我们都喜欢测量热电传输
the 1800s who like to measure thermal
and electrical transport anyway we can
实际上，除了珀尔帖效应是
actually I should comment here as a bit
of an aside that Peltier effect is
实际上，了解您的技术效果非常有用
actually a very technologically useful
effect to know about you can actually
用它建造一个非常好的没有移动部件的冰箱，这个想法是
build a very nice refrigerator with it
which has no moving parts the idea is
如果您想将热量从冰箱评价器的一侧转移到
that if you want to move heat from one
side the inside of your fridge rater to
冰箱的外部将热量转移出去
the outside of the refrigerator to move
heat out
你只需要运行电流，它就会带走热量，使这一面变冷
you just run current and it drags heat
with it and leaving this side cold
事实上，您可以购买这样构造的冰箱
making that side hot in fact you can buy
refrigerators that are built like this
他们没有水泵之类的东西他们不大声他们很安静
they don't have pumps and things like
that they're not loud they're very quiet
实际上，它们经常被用作葡萄酒冰箱，我不知道为什么，但是
frequently they're actually used as wine
refrigerators I don't know why but but
这些天，您可以在公开市场上购买Peltier冰箱，但是
you can buy a Peltier refrigerator you
know on the open market these days but
在Peltier冰箱中必须记住的一件事是
one thing that wuntch has to keep in
mind in a Peltier refrigerator is that
你不能使自己不能仅仅继续运行越来越多的电流，
you can't make you can't just keep
running more and more current and
越来越冷，因为在某个时候会有一个我
getting a colder and colder because at
some point there's going to be an I
平方R的散热量，因此您将消耗功率，如果我平方R
squared R heat dissipation so you'll be
dissipating power and if I squared R
变得太大，那么您就开始加热东西，所以对于小电流来说
gets too big then you start heating
things up so for small currents this
一侧会变冷一侧会变热但对于大电流而言
side will get cold this side will get
hot but for large currents everything
会变热，因此建造一台好的帕尔贴冰箱的艺术形式是
gets hot so the the art form in building
a good Peltier refrigerator is that you
必须找到一种具有大珀尔帖系数但很小的材料
have to find a material with a large
Peltier coefficient but a small
电阻率，找到这些材料的人很多
resistivity and there's many many people
whose job it is to find these materials
好吧，无论如何，我们将尝试计算此帕尔帖系数um
alright anyway we're going to try to
calculate this Peltier coefficient um
我们如何做得好，热电流密度JQ
how do we do that well the heat current
density JQ and we have the electrical
电流信号，我们知道电流密度是多少
current ensign we know what the
electrical current density is it's the
速度电子正在移动电子和电荷的密度
velocity electrons are moving the
density of the electrons and the charge
在电子上，热含量非常相似，
on the electrons the heat content see
very similar it's sort of a lot while
如果您老实说，这是三分之一，这是通常的情况
there's a factor of one-third if you're
honest about it that's a this usual
几何因素不必太担心
geometric factor don't worry about it
too much
电子的速度正在移动电子的密度和热量
the velocity electrons are moving the
density of the electrons and the heat
每个电子携带的是CVT
that each electron is carrying which is
CVT
我们将这两件事的比值求得珀尔帖系数pi为
we take the ratio of these two things
we'll get a Peltier coefficient pi is
如果插入通常的CV动力学理论结果，则CVT超过e的三倍
CVT over three times minus e if we plug
in the usual kinetic theory result of CV
是三分之二的KB，我要警告您，这不是一个好主意，我们最终会得到
is three-halves KB which I'm re warning
you is not a good idea we end up getting
KB的两倍乘以e乘以T，人们经常做的是
KB over two times minus e times T and
frequently what people do is they
实际考虑的比率称为s，即PI与T的比称为
actually consider the ratio known as s
which is PI over T s is known as the
塞贝克系数塞贝克是1800年代的另一个人，
Seebeck coefficient Seebeck was another
person from the 1800s who liked to
我相信他来自
measure electrical and thermal
properties he I believe he was from
爱沙尼亚实际上任何人无论如何都恰好是爱沙尼亚人，所以如果你把那个
Estonia actually anyone who happens to
be Estonian anyway so if you take that
我们只得到2倍减去e的通用常数KB
ratio we just get the universal constant
KB over 2 times minus e which has a
负0.4的数值乘以10至负10到负4伏
numerical value of minus 0.4 times 10 to
the minus 10 to the minus 4 volts per
开尔文（Kelvin），问题就在这里，如果您实际测量塞贝克（Seebeck）
Kelvin and the problem is here that if
you actually measure the Seebeck
您实际上发现的任何金属的系数s小100倍
coefficient for any metal you discover
actually actually s is 100 times smaller
所以这在动力学理论动力学中是一个明显得多的明显错误
so this is an obvious much more obvious
error in in kinetic theory kinetic
理论是错误的，这个问题的根源是我们正在使用
theory is going way wrong and the source
of this problem is that we were using
电子的热容量是错误的，问题就来了
this heat capacity for the electrons
that is just wrong and the problem comes
从为什么为什么这样的问题开始，因为实际上C比N大得多
from why why the problem by the problem
because in fact C over N is much much
如果少于三分之二kb的话，如果
less than three-halves kb c vo ran much
much less than three-halves kb well if
如果我们使用的热量如此之大，那是真的，为什么
this is true if we're using this heat
capacity that's so wrong why is it that
当我们计算热量时，我们向上计算的方法还可以
we did okay when we calculated way up
there when we calculated the thermal
导热率我们得到了导热率与常规导热率之比
conductivity we got the ratio of the
thermal conductivity to the regular
电导率我们得到的洛伦兹数几乎完全正确
conductivity we got the lorentz number
almost exactly right where is the
塞贝克的效率是完全错误的，所以
Seebeck
efficient is completely wrong so
某种程度上的矛盾或其他V需求弗朗兹定律即将到来
something's inconsistent somehow or
other the V demand Franz law is coming
正确，塞贝克系数完全错误，
out right the Seebeck coefficient is
coming out completely wrong and the
发生这种情况的原因我们获得了Vietminh Franz法律正确的原因
reason that this happens the reason we
got the Vietminh Franz law right reason
CAPA之所以正确的原因是因为我们犯了两个取消错误，两个取消
why why CAPA is right is because we made
two canceling errors two cancelling
错误，这是我提到的第一个vit C over n CV over N
errors there's the first one I've
mentioned already vit C over n CV over N
比kb的三分之二少得多，我们使用kb，但还有另一半
is much much less than three-halves kb
and we use kb but there's another one we
也使用V的V平方期望值，我们插入了动力学理论结果8
also use V squared expectation of V we
plugged in the kinetic theory result 8
KB T超过PI m，实际上V平方实际上要大得多
KB T over PI m and in actuality V
squared is actually much much greater
在导热系数方面比PI M的KB还要大，它们几乎
than a KB over PI M in these errors in
the thermal conductivity they almost
完全抵消，所以我们得到的导热系数几乎完全正确
exactly cancel so we get the thermal
conductivity almost exactly right
而这个V平方的量不会输入塞贝克系数，所以我们
whereas this quantity V squared doesn't
enter in the Seebeck coefficient so we
完全弄错了，因为我们使用了这个，但现在还不行
get it completely wrong because we use
this but not this okay now the first
一年中有机会赢得极好的奖品一种高质量的巧克力
chance of the year to win fabulous
prizes one very high quality chocolate
棒实际上我最喜欢的巧克力棒已经卖完了，所以这有点少了
bar actually my favorite chocolate bar
was sold out so this is a slightly less
而不是高质量的巧克力棒，所以如果有人可以告诉我我们为什么做
than a very high quality chocolate bar
so if anyone who can tell me why we made
这两个错误我们该怎么办我们会遗漏吗
both of these mistakes what do we do
wrong would we leave out come on come on
来吧来吧来吧来吧我们该怎么忘记某人某人是
come on come on come on come on what do
we forget someone someone yes
你还好，所以我不会成为那个巧克力棒，但这很好
you're okay so I'm not going to be the
chocolate bar for that but it's a good
通常使用V对X的期望的想法是UV平方
idea generally generally using
expectation of V versus X is UV squared
我们会犯一个错误，但是通常只是两种错误的一个因素，所以这是一个
we'll make an error buts usually only a
factor of two kind of error so it's a
小错误，因此有各种各样的争论，关于哪个更适合用于此
small error so there's various debates
as to which one is better to use in this
的情况，但我同意这是一个潜在的问题
case but I agree that that's a potential
problem
其他人是是是是费米子是，所以我会扔给
anyone else yes yes yes that's it
fermions yes so I would throw this to
你，但它可能会错过，所以你可以出来，然后再拿出来，所以
you but it would probably miss so you
can come it out and get it afterwards so
我们遗漏的是保利排斥原理电子是
the thing we left out was Pauli
exclusion principle electrons are
费米子不能使所有电子处于相同的状态，它们不是
fermions you can't put all the electrons
in the same state they're not a
无论如何，经典气体都有费米气体，所以我们将不得不
classical gas in any sense there are a
Fermi gas and so we're going to have to
妥善对待，也许能够读下来，因为它真的
treat that properly maybe able to read
that write that down because it's really
重要的费米统计费米统计，所以我们必须处理
important Fermi statistics Fermi
statistics so we have to deal with that
这就是我们下一步要做的，但是在此之前，您可以做一点
that's what we're going to do next but
before doing that you can do a little
犹大理论摘要犹大摘要um
bit of a summary of juda theory
juda summary um
所以提请总结很多事情，很多事情，很多运输
so drew to summary many things right
many things right many transport
正确的物业，我认为您要学习家庭作业，
properties you get right and I think for
homework you'll study a couple of other
在犹大理论中您正确的事情仍然被大量使用
things that you get right in judah
theory it's still used very heavily drew
该理论被广泛用于理解金属和半导体
the theory is used very heavily for
understanding metals and semiconductors
特别适用于半导体，但存在一些问题
particularly good for semiconductors but
it has problems and some of the problems
好吧，我们的H可能有错误的符号，错误的符号，您可以让CV超过
are well our H can have wrong sign have
wrong sign sign um you can have CV over
N实际上远小于我们使用的三分之二kb
N is actually much much less than
three-halves kb where we use
在计算中减少了三分之二kb，这样您就可以知道Seebeck错误
three-halves kb in the calculations and
you can get you know Seebeck wrong by
错误一百一百零零等等，实际上您可以得到
wrong by a hundred long by a hundred and
so forth in fact you can get the sign of
Seebeck系数也是错误的，但是由于我们被Mac和
the Seebeck coefficient wrong as well
but being that we're off by a mac and
幅度高达一百倍，似乎有点多余
magnitude by a factor of a hundred it
seems a little bit superfluous to worry
无论如何，关于标志的一切都突然好起来了，这些是其中的一些
about the sign all of a sudden okay
anyway so these are some of the
犹大理论的总结，但尽管如此，
summaries of juda theory but nonetheless
this was
人们如何在犹大之前的1900年代首次了解奖牌
how people understood medals for the
first time in the 1900s before Judah
人们根本不了解金属，但对理论仍然很满意
people didn't understand metals at all
and still do to theories extremely good
粗略了解金属的方法，但是大约25步并没有真正进展
way to roughly understand metals but
nothing really progressed for about 25
十年，犹大理论就存在了，人们不明白为什么这些
years and Judah theory was all there was
and people didn't understand why these
事情并没有解决，但是在1925年左右，先生
things didn't come out right
but around 1925 there are a lot of sir
物理上同时取得的巨大进步是1925年的Pauli排除法
simultaneous enormous advances in
physics 1925 was the Pauli exclusion
原理1926年是薛定inger方程，1926年是费米·狄拉克
principle 1926 was the Schrodinger
equation also 1926 was was Fermi Dirac
统计资料，1927年有人来了一个名叫Arnold Sommerfeld的家伙
statistics and in 1927 someone came
along guy named Arnold Sommerfeld 1927
索默菲尔德索默菲尔德获得诺贝尔奖提名81次从未失败
Sommerfeld Sommerfeld was nominated for
nobel prize 81 times never got it poor
家伙，但他的想法是他要用费米统计来治疗金属
guy but his idea was he was going to
treat metals with fermi statistics treat
用费米统计与费米统计换句话说就是
metals metals with fermi statistics with
fermi statistics in other words we're
将解释电子实际上是费米子这样的事实
going to account for the fact that the
electrons are actually fermions and so
现在，我们需要回顾一下关于费米的知识
now we have to do a little bit of a
review of what we know about fermi
统计数据，我们要记住的最重要的是费米
statistics and the most important thing
we have to remember is the Fermi
βε的职业函数n F减去mu比βε的e大1
occupation function n F of beta epsilon
minus mu is 1 over e to the beta epsilon
减亩加1处视图是化学势γ势和
minus mu plus 1 view here is the
chemical potential gamma potential and
这个NF事物NF是概率桶处于本征态的概率是一个鸡蛋。
this NF thing NF is the probability the
prob bin an eigenstate it's an egg an
鸡蛋能量在能量能量epsilon被占领
egg at energy at energy energy epsilon
is occupied
好是是问题否是好的好吧好吧，让我们来画这个东西
good yes yes question No yeah good all
right good so so let's plot this thing
所以我们在这个轴上有能量，在这个轴上还有NF
so we have energy on this axis we have
NF on this axis and somewhere over here
我们在零温度下的化学势μ费米函数
we have the chemical potential mu at
zero temperature the Fermi function goes
从一到零作为应该在那儿放平的阶跃函数
from one to zero as a step function
that's supposed to be flat up there so
这等于T等于零，这是从1下降到零的完美步骤
this is at T equals zero it's a perfect
step from one down to zero at the
T处的化学势不等于零，看起来更平滑
chemical potential at T not equal to
zero it's somewhat smoother looks like
因此，这是T大于零，并且宽度从一开始下降
this so this is T greater than zero and
the width over which it drops from one
设为零，这里的宽度大约是KBT好的，这看起来有点模糊吗
to zero that this width here is roughly
KBT okay does this look vaguely familiar
从去年开始，我希望是的，所以现在对
from last year
I hope yeah okay so now it's useful to
有几个定义，我们将使用定义化学
have a couple of definitions that we're
going to use definition the chemical
t处的电位mu等于零称为费米能量EF
potential mu at t equals zero is known
as is called the Fermi energy EF a Fermi
能量费米能量，您会发现很多东西都是以先生的名字命名的
energy Fermi energy you'll discover that
a lot of things are named after mister
Fermi好吧，现在我应该警告您，
Fermi okay now I should warn you that
there's some disagreement in the
书中有关您所谓的费米能量的文献
literature in the books as to what
you're supposed to call the Fermi energy
有人认为化学势和费米能是
some people think that the chemical
potential and the Fermi energy are
实际上，同义词是大多数人都相信的东西，我认为
actually synonymous mean the same thing
most people I believe think that the
0温度下的化学势是费米能，
chemical potential at 0 temperature is
the Fermi energy and that's the
我们将要使用的定义实际上是有意义的
definition we're going to work with it's
actually it makes sense to do that
因为为什么只用两个词来表示完全相同的事情
because why would you just have two
terms that mean exactly the same thing
如果您指的是化学势，就称其为化学势
just call it the chemical potential if
you mean chemical potential Kelvin
零温度下的电势我们称费米能为电子
potential at zero temperature we call
the Fermi energy for electrons which are
你知道自由电子波我们通常有H bar平方K平方
you know free electron waves we
generally have H bar squared K squared
如果您的波向量为K，则超过2m的能量就是能量
over 2m is the energy is an energy if
you have a wave with wave vector K its
能量将为H bar平方K平方超过2m，因此如果我们将其固定为
energy will be H bar squared K squared
over 2m so if we fix this thing to be
费米能量然后我们定义KF来满足这个方程，所以定义了KF
the Fermi energy then we define KF to
satisfy this equation so KF is defined
通过这个方程式，可以确定KF为费米动量费米动量
by this equation this defines KF is the
Fermi momentum fermi momentum so if we
知道费米能量我们只是从这个方程计算费米
know the Fermi energy we just calculate
from this equation what the Fermi
每个人都对此感到高兴，所以如果你想知道我们是否
momentum is okay everyone happy with
that all right so if you wonder if we
有一些物理系统，我们知道那个物理中有多少个电子
have some physical system we know how
many electrons are in that physical
我们写n的系统电子总数是所有电子的总和
system we write n the total number of
electrons is the sum over all
本征态数据ε的费米占有因子的本征态卵
eigenstates eggs of the Fermi occupation
factor of data epsilon of the eigenstate
减去亩，为什么我要这样写所以这是所有可能的总和
minus mu so why do I write it like this
so this is the sum over all possible
状态在系统中被占据的概率，以及
states in the system the probability
that that state will be occupied and if
对所有本征态求和，就得到了粒子的总数
you sum up over all eigenstates you get
the total number of particles in the
系统不错，是的，如果您知道
system good yeah you can also turn this
on the on its head if you know the
系统中粒子的数量，您可以使用此公式计算
number of particles in the system you
could use this equation to figure out
如果您必须像现在那样做，那么化学潜力是什么
what the chemical potential is if you
have to do that now as we did in the
德拜理论，我们不得不经常对所有可能的平面波求和，所以
Debye theory we had to frequently sum
over all possible plane waves so one
这时候我们应该熟悉的事情我向你保证，我们会用这个
thing we should be familiar with at this
time I promised you we would use this a
很多是所有可能的平面波的总和被D 3代替
lot is the sum over all possible plane
waves gets replaced by an integral a D 3
K超过2 PI的立方，因此每个本征态都是我们盒子中的特定平面波，因此
K over 2 PI cubed so every eigenstate is
a particular plane wave in our box so
总和成为2 pi乘以体积因子的整数d 3
the sum becomes an integral d 3 cubed
over 2 pi times a factor of the volume
唯一不同的是，我将前面的系数设为2
the only thing that's different is I'm
going to put a factor of 2 out front and
对于自旋，因子2是电子具有两个可能的自旋
the factor of 2 is for spins that
electrons have two possible spins in one
特定的平面波可以旋转或向下旋转，因此有两种可能
particular plane wave it can be either
spin up or spin down so two possible
状态，然后我们将费米因子beta epsilon K减去Mew ok
States and then we're integrating the
Fermi factor beta epsilon K minus Mew ok
到目前为止，还不错，所以在低温，低T下
so far so good
alright so at low temperature at low T
洛蒂这东西是一个阶梯功能这是阶梯
loti this thing here is a step function
this is step which the step function
会告诉我们，我们应该整合直到将第一相加直到
would tell us we should integrate up
until integrate the number one up until
能量就是费米能量，换句话说，所有电子都被充满
the energy is the Fermi energy in other
words all the electrons are filled all
这些州被充满在费米能量之下，而所有东西都被塞满
the states are filled below the Fermi
energy and everything above the Fermi
能量为空，所以我们可以重写n为2v，让我们拉出2个PI立方体
energy is empty so we can rewrite n is
2v let's pull out the 2 PI cubed
积分d3k小于K小于KF，因此说K的绝对值为
integral d3k up to K less than KF so
saying that the absolute value of K is
费米动量小于KF等于说能量必须是
less than KF the fermi momentum is
equivalent to saying the energy must be
小于费米能量好，是的，现在这告诉我们的是
less than the Fermi energy good yeah ok
now this what this is telling us is that
此处的填充状态填充状态形成半径KF的球，并且
the filled States here filled States
States form a ball ball of radius KF and
零温度下的充满状态通常又被称为费米海
filled States at zero temperature are
usually known as the Fermi sea again
以费米和球表面命名的东西被称为
something named after Fermi and the
surface of the ball surface is known as
费米表面，所以这种恐惧和球体周围的所有地方都是
the Fermi surface so this fear and
everywhere around the sphere are the
这个球的表面所有能量都是EF，所以如果您有一个半径球体
surface of this ball the energies are
all EF so if you have a sphere of radius
KF那个球体表面上的所有东西都具有相同的能量，并且
KF everything on the surface of that
sphere has the same energy and the
能量就是费米能量，好，所以我们要做的最后一件事就是
energy is the Fermi energy good alright
so last thing we have to do is we have
实际计算球与球的结合量，所以我们有2 V
to actually calculate the volume of that
sphere bond with a ball so we have 2 V
超过2个PI的立方，该积分的值只会给我们
over 2 PI cubed and the value of that
integral is just going to give us the
体积为4/3 pi KF立方，然后进行一些重新排列
volume which is 4/3 pi K F cubed and
then with a little bit of rearrangement
我们可以将V移交给该副律师
we can move the V over to this side
counsel
因子将在V上得到n，这是密度和电子密度e密度
factors will get n over V which is the
density and electron density e density
这是KF超过3 pi平方的立方，然后求解此KF将得到KF等于3
which is KF cubed over 3 pi squared then
solve this for KF will get KF equals 3
PI的平方乘以密度的1/3，所以如果我们知道电子的密度
PI squared times the density to the 1/3
so if we know the density of electrons
我们知道KF，然后我们可以将KF重新插入方程式中
we know KF and then we can plug KF back
in to our equation which I'm just about
向下滚动以获取EF，因此EF为H bar平方KF平方2 m
to scroll off the top to get EF so EF is
H bar squared K F squared over 2 m
等于H bar平方超过2m乘以3 pi平方n等于2/3，这是
equals H bar squared over 2m times 3 pi
squared n to the 2/3 and this is a
相当重要的方程式，我们稍后将使用它，它告诉我们什么是
rather important equation we're going to
use it later on so it tells us what is
费米能量的密度，所以你知道费米能量有多大
the Fermi energy in terms of the density
so you know how big is the Fermi energy
好吧，我们首先要弄清楚密度是多少
well let's first we have to figure out
what the density is
应该使用什么密度好让我们尝试每个原子大约1个电子的密度
what density should use well let's try
try density of about 1 electron per atom
至少对于福特Ruda理论而言，这似乎非常有效
which seemed to work pretty well for
Ford Ruda theory at least for some of
这些金属，如果我们这样说，对于铜II X铜，我们得到的EF为
these metals if we do that say for
copper II X copper we get EF is
大约7电子伏特，是个好数量还是个好数量
approximately 7 electron volts and is
that a big number or small number well
将其转换为费米温度非常有用
it's useful to convert it to a
temperature which is known as the Fermi
温度，所以我将再次定义费米温度
temperature so I'll define Fermi
temperature again something named after
费米温度TF等于EF超过KB，对于铜或铜TF约为
Fermi temp which is T F equals EF over
KB and for copper or copper TF is about
80,000开尔文
80,000 Kelvin
巨大的巨大巨大的巨大的费米能量和费米温度
huge huge huge huge so typical Fermi
energies and Fermi temperatures in
金属绝对是巨大的，其原因是
metals are absolutely enormous and the
reason for the
这是因为如果每个原子有一个电子，那么会有很多电子
this is because there's a lot a lot of
electrons if one electron per atom
当您开始将电子放入系统时，会有很多原子
there's a lot of atoms when you start
putting electrons into your system you
填充小的低能态首先是具有最小K的态，然后
fill up the small the low energy states
first the ones with smallest K but then
那些被填满了，你必须开始越来越多地填满
those are filled and you have to start
filling up higher and higher and higher
能量状态，当你把最后一个电子放进去的时候
energy states and by the time you put
that last electron in you've gotten up
消耗巨大的能量，因为这些电子的密度确实
to an enormous energy because the
density of these electrons is really
很大，所以让我们实际绘制费米
really big
so let's actually plot the Fermi
再次起作用，所以这里是F这里是EF这里的化学势
function again so here's an F here's one
here's EF the chemical potential
从KB中取出约80,000开尔文，费米功能将
approximately 80,000 Kelvin from take
out a KB and the Fermi function will
看起来像这样，它的范围很小，是KBT茶室
look like this it drops in a very very
small range this is KBT tearoom it's
比我画的还要夸张，比我画的还要窄
even more exaggerated than I've drawn
it's even narrower little drop than I've
然后我画了一下，因为这里的距离是8万
then I've drawn because this distance
here as a temperature is 80 thousand
开尔文与我们的室温300开尔文之间的距离
Kelvin versus our room temperature which
is 300 Kelvin so this distance over
费米函数从一下降到零的范围非常狭窄
which the the Fermi function drops from
from one to zero is a very very narrow
在费米表面的顶部银条，实际上这张图片给了我们
sliver at the top of the Fermi surface
and in fact this picture here gives us
已经暗示了为什么金属的热容量如此之低
already a hint as to why the heat
capacity of the metal is so low so much
比我们想像的要低，以具有热容量，您必须
lower than we would have guessed in
order to have heat capacity you have to
能够吸收一些能量，所以你想象一个电子处于本征态
be able to absorb some energy so you
imagine an electron in some eigenstate
它吸收一些能量，然后一点点跳到附近的本征态
it absorbs some energy and it jumps up
to a nearby eigenstate with a little
所有这些电子都在这里，它们吸收不了任何能量
more energy well all of these electrons
down here they can't absorb any energy
因为它们附近的所有本征态都已被填充，所以无处可去
because all the eigenstates near them
are already filled there's nowhere for
他们走了，他们完全冻结了，他们根本无法吸收任何能量
them to go they're completely frozen
they can't absorb any energy at all the
只有能吸收能量的东西才是费米表面附近的东西
only things that can absorb energy are
the things close to the Fermi surface
他们可能会跳到费米表面上方并吸收能量，因为
where they could jump above the Fermi
surface and absorb energy because
如果没有空的状态可以进入一个空状态
there's an empty state there for them to
go into if there's no empty state to go
他们根本无法吸收任何能量，因此给了我们一个提示
into there's no way they can absorb any
energy at all so that gives us a hint as
为什么热容量这么低最后一件事是我们可以看看
to why the the heat capacity is so low
one final thing is we can look at the
典型速度典型速度称为
typical velocity
typical velocity which is known as the
费米速度费米速度显然可以，VF可以是h-bar KF
Fermi velocity Fermi velocity apparently
right okay VF which would be h-bar K F
除以质量好的KF，如果把它放进去，就会得到很大的数目
divided by the mass okay K F and if you
put that in you get a huge number
巨大约等于光速的1％
huge equals huge approximately 1% of the
speed of light
这可能会让您感到惊讶，因为您曾经接触过的每种金属
which might surprise you this every
metal that you've ever run into contact
像铜，铅，银，钨，钨等具有电子的东西
with things like copper lead silver
tungsten whatever it is it has electrons
在它周围以一定速度奔跑时将具有光速的1％甚至更大
in it running around at speeds will have
1% the speed of light or even greater
现在这听起来让您感到惊讶，而实际上相对论开始变得
now that might sound surprising to you
and in fact relativity starts to become
重要的是，如果您以这些速度小心地做事，但实际上
important if you're doing things
carefully at those speeds but in fact
一想到有多少电子就不足为奇了
it's not surprising once you think about
how many electrons there are there are
每个原子一个或一个原子几个电子
tons and tons and tons of electrons one
per every atom or several per every atom
在某些情况下，所有低能状态都被您完全充满了
in some cases and so all the low energy
states are completely filled you just
必须不断建立越来越高的能量状态，
have to keep building up to higher and
higher and higher energy states and the
费米表面上的费米表面顶部的电子
electrons on the top of the Fermi
surface on the Fermi on the Fermi
费米球外边缘的表面异常高
surface in the outer edge of the fermi
ball are an extraordinarily high have
非凡的高能量，高动能，因此从外部
extraordinary high energy high kinetic
energy therefore externally a high
速度，我想我们停在那里，我想我周一见
velocity and I guess we stop there and I
guess I see you Monday
[掌声]
[Applause]